### **Enan Srivastava**

(630) 608-3688 enan332@gmail.com enan.rocks GitHub

Motivated and hard working student who is highly interested in pursuing a career and degree in Computer Science and Finance/Economics. Pursues interests through extracurriculars and side projects to gain relevant experience. Expected graduation:

May 2022

# **Skills**

- Software Development: Python, Java, JavaScript(Firebase, JQuery, React Native), NodeJS, Bootstrap, Git, Firebase, HTML5, UNIX Scripting, PHP, CSS, Wordpress.org, Bootstrap, CPanel Management, IT Services
- Proficient in MS Office Suite: Excel, Word, PowerPoint and Access

# **Experience**

### **Code Ninjas-**

Sensei- Teacher(April 2019-August 2019)

- Led classes and one on one sessions to teach Scratch and JavaScript to 7-14 y/o's
- Organized effective software and file management for 20 computers
- Provided IT Support on a small scale

A Colorful Affair- Website Consultant

- Optimized site to decrease load time
- SEO Optimization
- AdSense Optimization

### Weblinx Inc. -

Web Developer- Intern(June 2018-May 2019)

- Created and optimized PHP and CSS/SCSS files as per client requests in a team environment.
- Utilized Git SCM and SCRUM to complete projects.
- Defined and tested use case scenarios

# Oswego Robotics(FIRST FRC 2338) -

FLL & FTC Programming Mentor(2015-2019)

FRC Programming Lead(2017-2019)

- Led programming team in robot and web app development
- Mentored Junior High and High School teams in app and robot programming.
- Attended world championships 2016 and 2017
- GearScout and GearData(Data Graph) (Skills: HTML, JavaScript, Firebase, HTTP Requests)
  - Developed an app to scout and track Robotics teams at competitions taking in robot data and compiling statistics for different teams.

#### **Eagle Scout-**

(August 2006-June 2019)

- Organized and led a team to construct a Little Free Library
- Leadership: Assistant Senior Patrol Leader(1 year), Webmaster(1 year), Librarian(1 year), Den Chief(6 months)

## **Kendall County Democrats**-

Volunteer Web Developer- Intern(September 2018-December 2018)

- Redesigned Wordpress website with custom JavaScript and CSS
- Reduced website latency by 50%
- Implemented SEO and Google Analytics boosting site visibility
- Canvassed, phone banked and designed posters for candidates in the county for 2018 midterm election.

# **Yeezy Supply Bot**- Python

October 2017-January 2018

Created a bot utilizing Python and Selenium which automatically buys products of Yeezy Supply upon new arrival. This was created for Central Hype store in Naperville, Illinois. -Earned a score of 5 in AP Computer Science Principles as Create submission project.

## Student Attendance Script - JavaScript

November 2017 - December 2017

Developed a script that automatically generates inquiry emails from an excel sheet containing list of absent students. Presented the solution to Oswego East High School Administration and the implementation plan is under review.

## Smart AutoResponder - JavaScript

November 2017 - December 2017

Developed a script that automatically generates a response dependent on whether the sender is a student or staff member. In seasonal use by Oswego East Administration.

### Bitcoin Day Trader - Java

*June 2017 - September 2017* 

Created a Java application which takes Bitcoin market data and executes buy/ sell orders relying on Bitcoin fluctuations. (Personal Project)

# **Education**

#### The Ohio State University

August 2019 - Present

Entrepreneurship & Innovation Scholar, Expected May 2022, Projected Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Sciences and a Minor in Business Analytics. Current relevant classes: CSE 2221(Java), Physics1250

#### Oswego East High School

August 2015 - May 2019

AP Classes: Computer Science Principles(5), Computer Science, Calculus BC(3, AB: 4), Physics 1, Language & Composition(3), Microeconomics(4), Human Geography, Physics 2, Macroeconomics, Statistics, Literature. Leadership: President of Political Action Club, Model UN, and Young Democrats; Bipartisanship Chair Teenage Republicans; GPA: 3.85

# **Special Interests**

Robotics, Political Science, Economics, International Relations, Golf, Hiking, Rock n' Roll, EDM, Rap, Chess, & 3D Printing